[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Cool, so this is the data we're working with.
好的 这就是我们即将使用的数据
It's a pretty neat data set, and let's explore it a little bit more.
这是一份十分整洁的数据 让我们进一步研究它
So, in the lectures, Emily talked about building word counts.
在课上 艾米莉 (Emily) 已经讲了建立单词统计以及
And some of the challenges with word count.
其中的一些挑战
So let's start by taking a quick look at our word counts.
所以让我们从简单浏览一下单词统计开始
So for example, let's #Get the word
举个例子 让我们尝试取得
counts for the Obama article.
关于奥巴马 (Obama) 文章的单词统计
So we have an article on Wikipedia about Barack Obama.
我们在维基百科 (Wikipedia) 上能找到 一篇关于巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 的文章
And what we're gonna do first is just take a quick look at the word counts for
我们首先要做的是快速浏览一下本篇文章的
that article.
单词统计
So I'm going to take this Obama variable that we created, and
我将使用我们之前建的变量Obama
I'm going to add a new column to it called word_count.
我将向这个变量新添一列 并命名为Word_count
So this is going to store the word count for Barack Obama.
该列将会用来储存对巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 文章的单词统计
And we can do that by just calling.
我们直接调用它就可以实现储存了
You could write, as we showed in the classifications sentiment analysis
和我们在分类情感分析中说的一样 你可以编写
notebook, you could write the function yourself to compute the word counts.
你可以自己编写函数来计算单词统计
But we just have one ready for us in the text analytics toolbox.
我们在我们的文本分析工具栏中已经有一个现成的了
So we just gonna use it to get started quickly.
我就准备直接使用这个
So we just call count_words.
就叫做count_words
See this count_ngrams, we're just gonna count words, which in the unit grams,
看到另外一个选项了吗 别选他 就选words 会计算单个的单词
single words.
一个一个
And as input, we're gonna
函数的输入值
give it the Obama text.
是Obama['text']
So I've now done it.
搞定了
And let's take a quick look.
看一下
Let's just print the Obama word count.
打印出 obama['word_count']
And here we go.
我们去到这里
We've now printed the Obama word count.
这样我们就打印出了奥巴马单词计数word_count的结果了
And you see that operations appeared once, represent appears one,
你看到operations 出现了一次 represent 出现了一次
office appears two, unemployed appears one, and so on for various words.
office两次 unemployed一次 等等等等
And it's not super intuitive here.
这些结果看起来没什么冲击力
So we're gonna play with this a little bit, and in the process, I'm gonna show
所以准备继续深入
you a cute little data engineering trick that might be useful in other areas.
我将要给你看一个数据工程的小技巧
So let's, what we're gonna
下一步
do next is ##Sort the word count for
标题是 给单词计数排序
the Obama article.
我们要检查奥巴马这篇文章的TF/IDF
Now, here's something to understand a little bit better, if you notice the word
这样你就才能更好地理解
counts is really a dictionary this is the kind of the Python dictionary.
这个 单词计数是Python的一个字典
You are given a key, in this case, it's the word.
每一个单词是一个键
For example, Honolulu where he was born, weather, marriage and so on.
比如说Honolulu 也就是他出生的地方 天气 婚姻等等
And then, he has a value of 1, 2, 3, 5, 30, which is the count,
然后就是值 也就是单词的数量 在这里是1 2 3 5 30 等等
how often that word appeared.
也就是单词出现的次数
And so what we're going to do is sort this.
然后我们要做的就是排序
And to sort those words, we have to turn it into a table where one column
我们把他放到一张表里面 一列是单词
is the word, the key of the dictionary, and the second column is the count.
也就是字典的键 第二列就是计数
And then we're going to sort that table.
然后给这张表排序
So, the way to do this, this famous way to learn Python, but
排序的方式也是学习python的方法
let me show you a quick little trick that you will find useful.
但是我给你准备来个捷径
So I'm gonna createa new table called the, obama_word_count_table.
所以说我创建了一张表叫做obama_word_count_table
And what I'm gonna do is take this Obama and I'm just gonna select here,
然后在obama表里所有的列
out of all the columns in the Obama table, I'm gonna select the, word_count.
选择word_count
Because this will make the printing a little neater.
这样会让打印出的结果更加简洁
But you could have done that with the whole table too.
你当然你可以用整张表
And then, I'm gonna call a function called stack.
这里用到的函数叫做stack
And this function stack is extremely useful.
这个stack函数很有用
It takes one column of an SFrame that contains a dictionary, and
它把Sframe里面字典的一列取出
stacks it one of top of each other into multiple columns.
然后和另外几列一起放在一起
In this case, two columns.
在这个例子 一共两列
One for word, and the other one for count.
一列是单词 一列是计数
So we're gonna stack a particular column called word_count,
所以说我要堆叠在 一起的是单词计数word_count
the one that we really care about.
也就是我们最关心的一列
And it generates some new columns.
它会产生新的几列
So we have to call them, give them a name.
我们要给他们取个名字
So new_column_name, in this case there are two of them.
new_column_name 在这个例子中是两列
One I'm gonna call, word.
所以我就叫做 单词word
And another one, I'm just going to call count.
另一个家叫做计数 count
And if I execute this and we take a look at this table,
如果我执行 然后看一下
Obama word count table.head just the first few lines.
这张表的前几列
You'll see it shows words normalize, sought, combat, but it's not sorted.
你可以看到单词被整齐的放在了一起
It's not a sorted table.
但并没有被排序
So what we do next is just take this table and just sort it by the count.
所以下一步我们要根据计数进行排序
And we've seen this before, but it's pretty simple.
很简答的步骤
So I'm gonna take the Obama count table, and I'm gonna call the sort function.
调用sort函数 进行排序
And I'm gonna sort it by the count column.
根据count 这一列排序
Sort by count.
也就是根据计数排序
And I'm gonna say ascending=false.
然后我输入 asceding=false 进行降序排列
So, instead of sorting in an ascending order, one, two, three,
不是升序 像 1 2 3
like we'd normally sort, we're gonna sort in a descending order.
不是之前用的升序 而是降序
Three, two, one.
3 2 1
So, if I press Enter, you'll see the most common word is the,
输入回车 你可以看到最常见的是
followed by in, followed by and, of, to, his, eventually Obama.
the 然后是in and of to his 最后是奥巴马
And so, act, a, he.
然后是act a he
So those are not that informative.
这些单词都是没什么意义的
And in the lectures, when we were working with Emily on them, she covered the issue
在课程中 我们和Emily一起合作 她觉得这个情况
that these uninformative words can drown out the important words.
应该把那些没有信息的单词从重要单词中去除
And that's why we introduced the notion of tfidf.
这也是为什么我们要介绍TF IDF
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community